calendar: n.   历法，日历, historian: n.   历史学家, unique: adj. 无与伦比的
Lesson 38. The first calendar. Future historians will be in a unique position when they come to record the history of our own times.
第38课。第一个日历。未来的历史学家在记录自己时代的历史时将处于独特的位置。
steadily: adv. 不断地
They will hardly know which facts to select from the great mass of evidence that steadily accumulates.
他们几乎不知道从稳步积累的大量证据中选择哪些事实。
solely: adv. 唯一地, video: n.   录像, bewilder: v.   令人眼花缭乱
What is more, they will not have to rely solely on the written word. Films, videos, CDs and CD-ROMs are just some of the bewildering amount of information they will have.
而且，他们不必仅依靠书面词。电影，视频，CD和CD-ROM只是他们将拥有的一些令人困惑的信息。
historian: n.   历史学家
They will be able, as it were, to see and hear us in action. But the historian attempting to reconstruct the distant past has always faced with a difficult task.
他们将能够看到并听到我们的行动。但是，试图重建遥远过去的历史学家一直面临着一项艰巨的任务。
deduce: v.   推断，推理, scanty: adj. 不足的，贫乏的, clue: n.   线索, insignificant: adj. 不重要的, shed: v.   使流出，泻
He has to deduce what he can from the few scanty clues available. Even seemingly insignificant remains can shed interesting light on the history of early man.
他必须从可用的几个少数线索中推断出他能做的一切。即使看似微不足道的遗体也可能对早期人的历史展现出有趣的启示。
calendar: n.   历法，日历, historian: n.   历史学家, advent: n.   出现，到来，来临, agriculture: n.   农业
Up to now, historians have assumed that calendars came into being with the advent of agriculture.
到目前为止，历史学家认为日历是随着农业的出现而开始的。
For then man was faced with a real need to understand something about the seasons.
因为那时，人面临着真正需要了解季节的东西。
assumption: n.   假定，设想, dot: n.   小圆点
Recent scientific evidence seems to indicate that this assumption is incorrect. Historians have long been puzzled by dots.
最近的科学证据似乎表明该假设是不正确的。历史学家长期以来一直被点困惑。
symbol: n.   符号, engrave: v.   雕刻, ivory: n.   象牙制品, mammoth: n.   （古）长毛象, tusk: n.   獠牙，长牙，象牙
Lines and symbols which have been engraved on walls, bones, and the ivory tusks of mammoths.
刻在墙壁，骨头和象牙象牙上的线条和符号。
nomad: n.   游牧民
The nomads who made these markings lived by hunting and fishing during the last ice age which began.
在开始的最后一个冰河时代，制作这些标记的游牧民族通过狩猎和钓鱼生活。
About 35,000 BC and ended about 10,000 BC by correlating markings made in various parts of the world.
公元前约35,000，结束了约10,000公里，通过将世界各地的标记相关联。
phase: n.   月相，天相
Historians have been able to read this difficult code. They have found that it is connected with the passage of days and the phases of the moon.
历史学家能够阅读此困难的代码。他们发现它与几天的流逝和月球相关。
calendar: n.   历法，日历, primitive: adj. 原始的, depict: v.   描画，描绘
It is, in fact, a primitive type of calendar. It has long been known that the hunting scenes depicted on walls were not simply a form of artistic.
实际上，它是一种原始类型的日历。早就知道，墙上描绘的狩猎场景不仅仅是一种艺术形式。
Expression, they had a definite meaning. For they were as near as early man could get to writing.
表达，它们具有明确的含义。因为他们和早期的人一样接近写作。
It is possible that there is a definite relation between these paintings and the markings that.
这些绘画与标记之间可能存在明确的关系。
Sometimes accompany them. It seems that man was making a real effort to understand the seasons 20,000 years earlier than has.
有时会陪伴他们。看来，男人正在努力地了解20，000年的季节。
Been supposed.
被认为。